Steven Stutts

Canyon Lake, TX 78133
steven.stutts@snhu.edu
https://www.linkedin.com/in/sstutts316/
https://www.github.com/sstutts316/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A hardworking military veteran with four years of exceptional leadership skills. Applies software engineering principles to solve complex problems through using industry best practices and collaboration with classmates and industry expert mentor. Quickly learns new methods and incorporates them into class work using real-world scenarios. Seeks feedback and applies it to improve technical solutions. Additionally, understands various technologies such as hardware, software, networking, and operating systems and how they interact.

SKILLS

Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript (ES6+), Data Structures and Algorithms, Collaboration, Problem Solving

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science – Software Engineering Concentration Southern New Hampshire University, GPA 3.7

01/2021 - 09/2024

Springboard & Walmart Career Choice: Software Development Career Program

07/2023 - 04/2024

9-month intensive course in Front-End Development using ReactJS and the development of proficiency with data structures and algorithms and object-oriented programming

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Springboard & Walmart Career Choice: Software Development Career Program Student

07/2023 - 04/2024

-
- Completing 450+ hours of hands-on course material.
- Collaborates with 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight.
- Completion of an in-depth portfolio project.
- Mastered skills in front-end development using ReactJS and the development of proficiency with data structures and algorithms and object-oriented programming.

Supply Chain Maintenance Technician

10/2020 - Present

Walmart Distribution Center 6016

- Promoted from Freight Handler and Yard Driver to Maintenance Technician.
- Responsible for performing Preventive maintenance on all warehouse equipment.
- Responsible for being available for equipment breakdowns.
- Responsible for ensuring all warehouse equipment is running up to Walmart's standards.
- Responsible for ensuring downtime is minimal, and production is maximized.

PROFESSIONAL ASSOCIATIONS